<elements>
	<name>Sorcerer Unbound Optional Features</name>
	<!-- Extra Metamagic Options -->
	<element name="Adjudicating Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_ADJUDICATING_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WOTC_XGTE_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_DIVINE_SOUL</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Requirements: Divine Soul</p>
			<p>When you cast a spell, you can spend 2 sorcery point to cause targets of an alignment of your choice to be outlined in light. If they didn’t already make a saving throw against the spell, they must make a Charisma saving throw or become outlined in light until the end of your next turn. This light can be a colour of your choice. (Usually, green is for good, red is for evil, orange is for lawful, purple is for chaotic, and white is for neutrals.)</p>
			<p>The attack roll against an affected creature or object has advantage if the attacker can see it, and the affected creature or object can't benefit from being invisible. If any are successful, they immediately stop glowing.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="2 sorcery points">
			<description>WWhen you cast a spell, you can spend 2 sorcery points to cause targets of an alignment of your choice to be outlined in light. The attack roll against an affected creature or object has advantage if the attacker can see it, and the affected creature or object can't benefit from being invisible. If any are successful, they immediately stop glowing.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Lingering Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_LINGERING_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast a spell with an area-of-effect and duration of instantaneous, you can spend 1 sorcery point to alter the spell such that it persists until the start of your next turn. Creatures and objects already affected by the spell suffer no additional consequences, but those that enter the area will come under effect of the spell. Entering and exiting the area will not cause one to be affected again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1 sorcery point">
			<description>When you cast a spell with an area-of-effect and duration of instantaneous, you can spend 1 sorcery point to alter the spell such that it persists until the start of your next turn. Nothing can be affected multiple times.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Spreading Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_ENLARGED_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast a spell with a range of self and an area-of-affect, you can spend 3 sorcery points to increase its a parameter of its size by 5 ft.</p>
			<li><strong>Conical.</strong> The cone length increases by 5 feet.</li>
			<li><strong>Line.</strong> The line width increases to 10 feet.</li>
			<li><strong>Circular/Spherical</strong> The radius increases by 2.5 feet.</li>
			<li><strong>Square, Cubic.</strong> The length of each face increases by 5 feet.</li>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="3 sorcery point">
			<description>When you cast a spell with a range of self and an area-of-affect, you can spend 2 sorcery points to increase its size slightly.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Delayed Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_DELAYED_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>WWhen you cast a spell that affects one or more points or directions (such as bonfire, burning hands, and sword burst), you can spend 1 sorcery point to delay its effect up to a number of rounds equal to your proficiency bonus. It becomes a magical mote at the origin (for lines and cones) or center (for circles and squares). The space must be unoccupied. It can then be activated as an action on your turn (or as a reaction, if the action was readied) for the spell to be cast from the mote’s location. Any decisions needed for the spell is made when it was cast. For example, using mold earth to create difficult terrain in a certain spot. </p>
			<p>You can have multiple delayed spells active, but you may only activate one at a time. You do not need to concentrate on these spells until they activate. If a creature were to touch a mote, they must make a Dexterity saving throw to back away or avoid contact. On a failed save, the spell activates. They can be dispelled, and counterspell requires vision on the mote, not yourself. If a spell creates multiple motes, they activate together simultaneously.</p>
			<p class="indent"> You can use Delayed Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell..</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1 sorcery point">
			<description>When you cast a spell that targets one or more points or directions, you can spend 1 sorcery point to delay it for up to {{metamagic delayed spell:timer}} (minimum 1) rounds.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="metamagic delayed spell:timer" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="metamagic delayed spell:timer" value="proficiency" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Elemental Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_ELEMENTAL_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<description>
			<p><i>They really looked at people who wanted to play specialized elementalists and said no.</i></p>
			<p>Choose a damage type from among the following types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison, thunder.</p>
			<p>When you cast a spell that deals a type of damage from among acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison, thunder, you can change it to your chosen type. This doesn’t count to the number of Metamagic options used.</p>
			<p>When you cast a spell that deals the chosen type of damage, or that was changed to do so, you can spend 1 sorcery point to add your charisma modifier to the damage (minimum of 0).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1 sorcery point">
			<description>When you cast a spell, you can spend change the damage type of an elemental spell to one that you've chosen and still use other metamagic options; And/Or when casting a spell with (or was changed to) the chosen damage type, spend 1 sorcery point to increase its damage by {{metamagic elemental spell:damage}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="metamagic elemental spell:damage" value="0" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="metamagic elemental spell:damage" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Amplified Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_AMPLIFIED_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<description>
			<p><i>Now here's the actual Heightened Spell. It's a bit weak and still doesn't do what it was meant to, but hey it cheats on some action economy.</i></p>
			<p>When you cast a spell that has effects based on the spell slot level used, you can spend up to 3 sorcery points to increase the effective spell slot level by that much. This cannot exceed the highest level of a spell you could normally cast.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="≤3 sorcery points">
			<description>When you cast a spell that has effects based on the spell slot level used, you can spend sorcery points to increase the effective spell slot level by that much, up to the highest level of a spell you could normally cast.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Balanced Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_BALANCED_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_CLOCKWORK_SOUL</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Requirements: Clockwork Soul Origin</p>
			<p>When you cast a spell which rolls for its result, such as with damage or healing, you can spend 1 sorcery point to use a static number instead. Use half the maximum value of each die rolled for the spell.</p>
			<p>This does not work for spells which specify ability checks, such as Counterspell.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1 sorcery point">
			<description>When you cast a spell which rolls for an effect, instead use half the maximum value of its dice.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Breath Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_BREATH_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_DRACONIC_BLOODLINE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Requirements: Draconic Origin</p>
			<p>When you cast a spell which does damage in only the type associated with your Dragon Ancestor, you can spend 1 sorcery point to instead cast it with a range of self(15-feet cone). Creatures and objects must make a saving throw against the spell if they wouldn’t already; On a failure, they take its full effects. On a success, they take half the total damage and no additional effects. Each damage type has a different saving throw as follows:</p>
			<li style="margin-left:1em;text-indent:-1em;"><strong>Acid.</strong> Constitution.</li>
			<li style="margin-left:1em;text-indent:-1em;"><strong>Cold.</strong> Constitution.</li>
			<li style="margin-left:1em;text-indent:-1em;"><strong>Fire.</strong> Dexterity.</li>
			<li style="margin-left:1em;text-indent:-1em;"><strong>Lightning.</strong> Dexterity.</li>
			<li style="margin-left:1em;text-indent:-1em;"><strong>Poison.</strong> Constitution.</li>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1 sorcery point">
			<description>When you cast a spell which does damage in only the type associated with your Dragon Ancestor, you can spend 1 sorcery point to instead cast it with a range of self(15-feet cone).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Horrifying Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_HORRIFYING_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_ABERRANT_MIND</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Requirements: Abberant Mind Origin</p>
			<p>When you cast a spell, you can spend 2 sorcery points to cause a chosen creature affected by the spell to make a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened until the start of your next turn. If the spell already has a Wisdom saving throw, they become frightened in addition to the spell’s normal effects until the start of your next turn on a failure.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="2 sorcery points">
			<description>When you cast a spell which does damage, you can spend 2 sorcery points to deal half its maximum potential damage instead of rolling.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Obscuring Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_OBSCURING_SPELL">
	<supports>Metamagic</supports>
	<requirements>ID_WOTC_XGTE_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_SHADOW_MAGIC</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Requirements: Shadow Magic</p>
			<p>When you cast a spell with an area-of-effect, you can spend 2 or 3 sorcery points to cause the spell to leave behind a zone of magical shadow. The light level in the area of the spell goes down by one tier: From bright to dim, from dim to dark. It fades at the start of your next turn unless you spent 2 sorcery points for it to last until the spell ends. You can see in the area of this magical darkness as if it were one tier higher.</p>
			<p class="indent">If any of this spell's area overlaps with an area of light created by another spell of its level or lower, the spell that created the light is dispelled.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="2 or 3 sorcery points">
			<description>When you cast a spell with an area-of-effect, you can spend 2 or 3 sorcery points to cause the spell to leave behind a zone of magical shadow. The light level in the area of the spell goes down by one tier: From bright to dim, from dim to dark. It fades at the start of your next turn unless you spent 2 sorcery points for it to last until the spell ends. You can see in the area of this magical darkness as if it were one tier higher. It also dispels weaker magical light.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Intuitive Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_INTUITIVE_SPELL">
	<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast a spell that requires concentration or maintain concentration for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to have it instead require 1 sorcery point at the start of each round you maintain its effects without concentration. On later rounds, you can end this Metamagic at any time on your turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use Intuitive Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1 sorcery point">
			<description>When you cast a spell that requires concentration or maintain concentration for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to have it instead require 1 sorcery point at the start of each round you maintain its effects without concentration.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Siphoning Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_SIPHONING_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast a spell that deals damage, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain 3 temporary hit points for each of its levels.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1 sorcery point">
			<description>When you cast a spell that deals damage, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain 3 temporary hit points for each of its levels.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Unstable Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_UNSTABLE_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_WILD_MAGIC</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Requirements: Wild Origin</p>
			<p>When you cast a spell that goes wild, you can spend 1 sorcery point to use another Metamagic option on it as if it hadn’t (you still spend sorcery points for the other). </p>
			<p>When you cast a spell, you can spend 3 sorcery points to force it to go wild.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1 or 3 sorcery points">
			<description>When you cast a spell that goes wild, you can spend 1 sorcery point to use another Metamagic option on it as if it hadn’t; or spend 3 sorcery points to force it to go wild.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Tempestuous Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_VORTEX_SPELL">
		<supports>Metamagic</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WOTC_SCAG_ARCHETYPE_STORM_SORCERY</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Requirements: Storm Origin</p>
			<p>When you cast a spell with an area of affect, you can spend 2 sorcery points to cause air in its space to become violently displaced. Each creature must make a Strength saving throw or be pulled or pushed 5 feet away from the spell’s centre or fall prone. If the spell already has a Strength saving throw, they are pushed or fall prone in addition to the spell’s normal effects until the start of your next turn on a failure.</p>
			<p>A line spell’s centre is along its width, not length.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="2 sorcery points">
			<description>When you cast a spell with an area of affect, you can spend 2 sorcery points to cause creatures and objects to be pulled or pushed 5 feet away from the spell’s centre or fall prone</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<!-- Unbound Spell List -->
	<element name="Spellcasting Unbound" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_SPELLCASTING_SORCERER">
		<description>
			<p><i>What was changed here is that you also have wizard's spell list.</i></p>
			<p>You get access to Wizard's spell list.</p>
		</description>
		<spellcasting name="Sorcerer" extend="true">
			<extend>Wizard</extend>
		</spellcasting>
		<sheet display="false"/>
	</element>
	<element name="Sorcerer, LV01: Unbound Spell List (Sorcerer)" type="Item" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_ITEM_OCF_SORCERER_SPELLCASTING_SORCERER">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_SPELLCASTING_SORCERER" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">first level, 1st level, spellcasting</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_SPELLCASTING_SORCERER" requirements="[level:sorcerer:1]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<!-- Unbound Font of Magic -->
	<element name="Partial Replenishment" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_PARTIAL_REPLENISHMENT">
		<description>
			<p><i>2nd-level sorcerer feature.</i></p>
			<p>When you complete a short rest, you can spend a number of hit dice to replenish a number of sorcery points equal to half the maximum value of each die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Hit Dice">
			<description>When you complete a short rest, you can spend a number of hit dice to replenish a number of sorcery points equal to half the maximum value of each die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sorcerer, LV02: Partial Replenishment" type="Item" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_ITEM_OCF_SORCERER_PARTIAL_REPLENISHMENT">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_PARTIAL_REPLENISHMENT" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">second level, 2nd level, metamagic</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_PARTIAL_REPLENISHMENT" requirements="[level:sorcerer:2]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
		<!-- Unbound Metamagic -->
	<element name="Metamagic Unbound" type="Class Feature" source="UNBOUND" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_UNBOUND">
		<description>
			<p><i>3rd-level Sorcerer optional feature</i></p>
			<p>You get an additional Metamagic option at 3rd level. At 10th level, you can use up to two Metamagic options on a spell unless otherwise noted.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Metamagic" supports="Metamagic" level="3" number="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADVANCED_METAMAGIC" requirements="[level:sorcerer:10]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Advanced Metamagic" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADVANCED_METAMAGIC">
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, your efficacy with altering the properties of your spells allows you to use two Metamagic options of a spell when you cast it, unless otherwise noted.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use an additional Metamagic options on a spell when you cast it, unless otherwise noted.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sorcerer, LV03: Metamagic Unbound" type="Item" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_ITEM_OCF_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_UNBOUND">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_UNBOUND" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">second level, 2nd level, metamagic</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_UNBOUND" requirements="[level:sorcerer:2]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<!-- Magical Fortitude -->
	<element name="Magical Fortitude" type="Class Feature" source="TCE" id="ID_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_MAGICAL_FORTIUTUDE">
		<description>
			<p><i>5th-level sorcerer feature, which replaces the Magical Guidance feature.</i></p>
			<p>At 5th level, you can directly tap into your inner strength to fuel your spells. As a bonus action on your turns, you can gain a level of exhaustion to regain a number of sorcery points equal to your proficiency bonus. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>Gain a level of exhaustion to regain {{magical fortitude:value}} sorcery points.</description>
			</sheet>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
		<stat name="magical fortitude:value" value="proficiency" bonus="base"  />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sorcerer, LV05: Magical Fortitude" type="Item" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_ITEM_OCF_SORCERER_MAGICAL_FORTITUDE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_MAGICAL_FORTIUTUDE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">fifth level, 5th level, sorcery points</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_MAGICAL_FORTIUTUDE" requirements="[level:sorcerer:5]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<!-- Signature Metamagic -->
	<element name="Signature Metamagic" type="Class Feature" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_SIGNATURE_METAMAGIC">
		<description>
			<p>At 20th level, your familiarity with bending the properties of your magic spells allows you to do so with ease. Choose one metamagic option you know and reduce its cost by 2 (minimum 0), or choose two and reduce their costs by 1 each (minimum 0).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>A chosen metamagic option has its cost reduced by 2 (minimum 0); Or two chosen metamagics have their costs reduced by 1 each (minimum 0).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sorcerer, LV20: Signature Metamagic" type="Item" source="Unbound" id="ID_UNBOUND_ITEM_OCF_SORCERER_SIGNATURE_METAMAGIC">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_SIGNATURE_METAMAGIC" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">twentyth level, 20th level, sorcery points, metamagic</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_UNBOUND_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_SIGNATURE_METAMAGIC" requirements="[level:sorcerer:20]"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_SORCERER_SORCEROUS_RESTORATION" requirements="[level:sorcerer:20]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>