<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Ancestries</name>
		<description>Various revised and new ancestries for Sellswords' Basin</description>
		<update version="0.0.11">
			<file name="ancestries.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aKromatopzia/Kolours-Aurora-Index/main/Sellswords-Setting/ancestries.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Yuan-Ti (Serpent Lower Body)" type="Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACE_YUAN_TI_SERPENT">
		<description>
			<p>Yuan-ti were originally humans who transformed themselves into serpent folk through ancient rituals. Most yuan-ti were corrupted into monsters by those rites, but some yuan-ti instead became a new people who mix characteristics of humans and snakes.</p>
			<h4>YUAN-TI TRAITS</h4>
			<p>All nagas share the following traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase. </i></b>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Alignment. </i></b>Most naga are either neutral or neutral evil in alignment.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Size. </i></b>Yuan-Ti with serpentine lower halves typically stand about 5 feet tall when upright, but the total length of their bodies, head to tail, ranges from 10 to as much as 20 feet. Your size is Medium.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Speed. </i></b>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Natural Weapons. </i></b>Your fanged maw and constricting serpentine body are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with your bite, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, and your target must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save, the target takes 1d4 poison damage. If you hit with your constrict attack, you deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, and you can attempt to grapple the target.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Binding Coils.</i></b>Creatures you grapple are restrained,</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Speed Burst. </i></b>By lowering your body to the ground and propelling yourself with your arms, you can move more quickly for a time. As a bonus action on your turn, if you have both hands free, you can Dash.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Poison Immunity. </i></b>You are immune to poison damage and can’t be poisoned.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Poison Affinity. </i></b>You gain proficiency with the poisoner’s kit.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Languages. </i></b>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for your character.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution" value="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<stat name="intelligence" value="1" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +2 (Naga)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 2" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +1 (Naga)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_NATURAL_WEAPONS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_SPEED_BURST" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_POISON_IMMUNITY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_POISON_AFFINITY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_BINDING_COILS" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language (Yuan-ti)" supports="Custom Race Language"  requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Yuan-ti)" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Natural Weapons" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_NATURAL_WEAPONS">
		<description>
			<p>Your fanged maw and constricting serpentine body are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with your bite, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, and your target must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save, the target takes 1d4 poison damage. If you hit with your constrict attack, you deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, and you can attempt to grapple the target.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your fanged maw and constricting serpentine body are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with your bite, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d4 + {{strength:modifier}}, and your target must make a Constitution saving throw (DC {{naga-poison:dc}}). On a failed save, the target takes 1d4 poison damage. If you hit with your constrict attack, you deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + {{strength:modifier}}, and you can attempt to grapple the target.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="naga-poison:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="naga-poison:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="naga-poison:dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Poison Immunity" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_POISON_IMMUNITY">
		<description>
			<p>You are immune to poison damage and the poisoned condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are immune to the poisoned condition.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Poison Affinity" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_POISON_AFFINITY">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with the poisoner’s kit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You gain proficiency with the poisoner’s kit.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_POISONERS_KIT" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Simple Weapon or Tool" supports="Simple||Tool" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Speed Burst" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_SPEED_BURST">
		<description>
			<p>By lowering your body to the ground and propelling yourself with your arms, you can move more quickly for a time. As a bonus action on your turn, if you have both hands free, you can Dash.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>On your turn, if you have both hands free, you can Dash.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Binding Coils" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORD_RACIAL_TRAIT_YUAN_TI_BINDING_COILS">
		<description>
			<p>Creatures you have grappled are restrained.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Creatures you have grappled are restrained.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!--Ratfolk Race (by Dirt)-->
	<element name="Ratfolk" type="Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RATFOLK">
		<description>
			<p>A colloquial term for rat-like humanoids from the Feywild. Despite their origins, they are not themselves fey nor magically-attuned. As with other beastkin, their culture is partially defined by their animalistic aspects, and how others may see them.</p>
			
			<h4>Wiry and Lanky</h4>
			<p>Ratfolks are a rodent-like humanoids. They are shorter than humans, and appear almost frail. They have heads shaped like rats, with an elongated skull, thin lips, a rat's snout, and monocoloured beads for eyes. The fur that grows on their bodies is usually thin, and commonly comes in a range from light browns to dark gray and black. </p>
			
			<h4>Life in the Shadow</h4>
			<p>Due to their association with rats, they are generally avoided by the aristocracies of human settlements, but can find places amongst the elves and dwarves for example. They are usually a nocturnal folk but, contrary to popular beliefs, are not sensitive to light.</p>
			
			<h4>A Place in the World</h4>
			<p>Although not a people with great history, only having made a presence after the Era of Upheavals, there are a decent number of ratfolk communities. They tend to stay with each other in great families, both for cultural reasons, and the societal one that they have poor reputations. Many ratfolk families end up in the protective of Cormyr, but just as many work with the seedy underbellies of cities such as Westgate and Neverwinter.</p>
			<h4>RATFOLK TRAITS</h4>
			<p>The ratfolk character is a race that focuses on several traits, holding these to be common ground among the vast majority of their race.</p>
			<p>Quick and silent, ratfolk exist as outsiders no matter where they are, but they let nothing get in their way.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Creature Type.</em></strong> You are a Humanoid.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Ratfolk look thin and frail, standing about 5'3” and 5'6”, and weighing around 110–120 lbs. Your size is Medium.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 35 feet. Ratfolk are quick on their feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Ratfolk are strongly inclined to follow their own path, preferring freedom over all else, which makes them strongly chaotic. Ratfolk are rarely evil, but most are morally neutral.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Ratfolk commonly live a due to quick reproduction and harsh environment and social practices little over 50 years, maintaining good vitality and longevity toward the end. Ratfolk reach adulthood at age 15, with the fur on their bodies turning grey once they've lived about 30 years.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> You are used to dark areas, and your eyes have adjusted to such. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of grey.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sneaky.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Stealth skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Thin Frame.</em></strong> You can squeeze through spaces as if you were one size smaller, and you have advantage on the Tumble action against creatures larger than yourself.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> Ratfolk are a varied lot, and tend to adapt to their environment. Choose a subrace from between urban and wild.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Improvement Option (Ratfolk)" supports="Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="35" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
		
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_RATFOLK_THIN_FRAME" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_RATFOLK_SUBRACE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Thin Frame" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_RATFOLK_THIN_FRAME">
		<supports>Ratfolk</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can squeeze through spaces as if you were one size smaller, and you have advantage on the Tumble action against creatures larger than yourself.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can squeeze through spaces as if you were one size smaller, and you have advantage on the Tumble action against creatures larger than yourself.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!--Urban or wild Choice-->
	<element name="Ratfolk Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_RATFOLK_SUBRACE">
		<supports>Ratfolk</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Ratfolk are separated into two subraces, colloquially described as sneaks and n, which come with different benefits. Choose one of these subraces.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Ratfolk Subrace" supports="Ratfolk" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<!--Urban Ratfolk Subrace-->
	<element name="Urban Ratfolk" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_SUBRACES_URBAN_RATFOLK">
		<supports>Ratfolk</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Ratfolk communities in cities tend to become notorious for their role as thieves and informants. Leveraging their cunning and speed to avoid danger as it comes.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Charisma score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Duplicity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Deception skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skulker.</em></strong> While you are in darkness or dim lighting, you have advantage on stealth checks to remain hidden.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_SKULKER" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<!--Skulker-->
	<element name="Skulker" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_RATFOLK_SKULKER">
		<description>
			<p>While you are in darkness or dim lighting, you have advantage on stealth checks to remain hidden.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While you are in darkness or dim lighting, you have advantage on stealth checks to remain hidden.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!--Wild Ratfolk Subrace-->
	<element name="Wild Ratfolk" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_SUBRACES_WILD_RATFOLK">
		<supports>Ratfolk</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Wild ratfolk live in nature, keeping to their feywild origins. They are not averse to society - as many do end up assisting and joining druidic covens, but may find prejudice due to the reputation of their other kind regardless. They may also take up nomadic lives of traders and scavengers.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Keen Senses.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sure-Footed.</em></strong> When you take the Dash action, and on your first turn of combat encounters, opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage and natural difficult terrain doesn't require extra movement.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_SURE_FOOTED" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	
	<!--Sure-Footed-->
	<element name="Sure-Footed" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_RATFOLK_SURE_FOOTED">
		<description>
			<p>You don't get stopped easily. When you take the Dash action, and on your first turn of combat encounters, opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage and natural difficult terrain doesn't require extra movement.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you take the Dash action, and on your first turn of combat encounters, opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage and natural difficult terrain doesn't require extra movement.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!--Hengeyokai-->
	<element name="Hengeyokai" type="Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_HENGEYOKAI">
		<description>
			<p>Myths from Kara-Tur, travellers to the Feywild, and rarely in the Forgotten Realms, speak of people who lure them into deep forests to be killed by forest spirits. Although many of those may be true on their own, hengeyokai ne'er-do-wells tend to be responsible for those stories.</p>
			<p>Despite being fey, they are not native to the Feywilds. Rather, they came from a blending of deific and fey influence on the eastern continent.</p>
			
			<h4>Elusive Shapechangers</h4>
			<p>As fey, they have habits against presenting as their 'true', hybrid, selves. And although they can seamlessly shift between their formes, hengeyokai may have a 'preferred' appearance other than their hybrid self.</p>
			<p>For their abilities however, they are ever-scrutinized in their homeland of Kara-Tur.</p>
			
			<h4>HENGEYOKAI TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Hengeyokai are varied and specialized as they come, with the following racial traits in their hybrid and humanoid forms.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Creature Type.</em></strong> You are a Fey and Humanoid, with the shapechanger subtype.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Being Fey, hengeyokai are extremely long-lived, being up to about 100 years old, and reach maturity at 15.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> Their Fey heritage allows hengeyokai to see in the dark to a limited capacity. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of grey.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Deception.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Wild Tongue.</em></strong> Hengeyokai in animal or hybrid form can communicate simple commands and concepts to natural beasts and fey beasts with the same form or a closely related form, for example, dogs to wolves. Beasts will not necessarily obey hengeyokai or even be friendly, however. Hengeyokai in humanoid form cannot communicate with such beasts but can understand them.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Nature's Mask.</em></strong> As an Action, a hengeyokai can shift between their various forms. This transformation is as the <i>Polymorph</i> spell, with the following caveats:</p>
			<ul>
			<li> Your hybrid and humanoid forms are Medium in size, while your animal form is a Tiny beast. You retain the shapechanger subtype.</li>
			<li> Each of your forms are the same when you shift to them; Your animal form is a Tiny beast and your humanoid form is a human who has one or two bestial features, while your hybrid form sesembles an anthropomorphic animal; You choose the appearance of all three forms as you create this character</li>
			<li> You retain identifying physical features such as a notch in your ear, or a scar on your face;</li>
			<li> Clothing and equipment are not subsumed into each transformation's forms, although may shift in position (but not size) for each of your forms;</li>
			<li> You mental ability scores are your own, while your physical ability scores are that of the animal's plus any modifiers you may have from other features. (Note: Pure ASI is a feature.);</li>
			<li> You retain your racial features and proficencies while in your animal form, and if it has Darkvision increase its ranges by 15ft.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write standard or kara-turan language, and one other language.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Aspect.</em></strong> The affinities of hengeyokai vary based on their animal aspect Choose one.</p>
			
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Improvement Option (Hengeyokai)" supports="Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Kara-Tur)" supports="Standard||Kara-Tur" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Kara-Tur)" supports="Standard||Exotic||KAra-Tur" />
		
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_WILD_TONGUE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_NATURES_MASK" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Wild Tongue -->
	<element name="Wild Tongue" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_WILD_TONGUE">
		<description>
			<p>Hengeyokai in animal or hybrid form can communicate simple commands and concepts to natural beasts and fey beasts with the same form or a closely related form, for example, dogs to wolves. Beasts will not necessarily obey hengeyokai or even be friendly, however. Hengeyokai in humanoid form cannot communicate with such beasts but can understand them.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Hengeyokai in animal or hybrid form can communicate simple commands and concepts to natural beasts and fey beasts with the same form or a closely related form, for example, dogs to wolves. Beasts will not necessarily obey hengeyokai or even be friendly, however. Hengeyokai in humanoid form cannot communicate with such beasts but can understand them..</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_LANGUAGE_WILD_TONGUE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Wild Tongue" type="Language" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Set Dressing" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_LANGUAGE_WILD_TONGUE">
		<supports>SPECIAL</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Hengeyokai in animal or hybrid form and Zakhara can communicate simple commands and concepts to natural beasts and fey beasts with the same form or a closely related form, for example, dogs to wolves. Beasts will not necessarily obey hengeyokai or even be friendly, however. Hengeyokai in humanoid form cannot communicate with such beasts but can understand them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="exotic">true</set>
			<set name="script">-</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Nature's Mask -->
	<element name="Nature's Mask" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_NATURES_MASK">
		<description>
			<p>As an Action, a hengeyokai can shift between their various forms. This transformation is as the <i>Polymorph</i> spell, with the following caveats:</p>
			<ul>
			<li> Your hybrid and humanoid forms are Medium in size, while your animal form is Tiny. You retain the shapechanger subtype.</li>
			<li> Each of your forms are the same when you shift to them; Your animal form is a Tiny beast and your humanoid form is a human who has one or two bestial features, while your hybrid form sesembles an anthropomorphic animal; You choose the appearance of all three forms as you create this character</li>
			<li> You retain identifying physical features such as a notch in your ear, or a scar on your face;</li>
			<li> Clothing and equipment are not subsumed into each transformation's forms, although may shift in position (but not size) for each of your forms;</li>
			<li> You mental ability scores are your own, while your physical ability scores are that of the animal's plus any modifiers you may have from other features. (Note: Pure ASI is a feature.);</li>
			<li> You retain your racial features and proficencies while in your animal form, and if it has Darkvision increase its ranges by 15ft.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="At-Will">
			<description>As an Action, a hengeyokai can shift between their various forms. This transformation is as the <i>Polymorph</i> spell, except your equipment do not shift with you; your beast form's mental ability scores do not change; your beast form's physical ability scores are your form's scores in addition to ASIs from your class features or similar; If your beast form would have darkvision, it has an additional 15ft.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- Animal aspect choice -->
	<element name="Hengeyokai Aspect" type="Racial Trait" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Hengeyokai come in various animal aspects, each with their own affinities.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Hengeyokai Aspect" supports="Hengeyokai" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Cat-->
	<element name="Feline Hengeyokai" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_RAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT_FELINE">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a feline aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny cat. Your humanoid form might have cat ears, a cleft lip, a cat's tail, or such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skill Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Acrobatics.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You have a feline aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny cat.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS" />
			<stat name="innate speed:misc" value="5" bonus="Aspect" requirements="[innate speed:1]" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Canine-->
	<element name="Canine Hengeyokai" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT_CANINE">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a feline aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny dog. (Yes, I know there isn't actually one.) Your humanoid form might have dog ears, pronounced canines, a dog's tail, or such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skill Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Insight.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You have a canine aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny dog.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Piscine-->
	<element name="Piscine" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT_PISCINE">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a piscine aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny fish. Your humanoid appearance might have vestigial fins, scaly patches, or such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skill Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Athletics.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You have a piscine aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny fish.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Melinae-->
	<element name="Melinae Hengeyokai" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT_MELINAE">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a melinae aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny badger. Your humanoid appearance might have melanized eyespots, badger ears, or such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skill Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Athletics.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You have a melinae aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny badger.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Monke-->
	<element name="Simian Hengeyokai" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT_SIMIAN">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a simian aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny monkey. (Yes I know they aint real.) Your humanoid appearance might have a monkey's nose, be strangely hairy, or such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skill Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Athletics.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You have a simian aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny monkey.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Avian-->
	<element name="Avian Hengeyokai" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT_AVIAN">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a simian aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny crow, owl, hawk, or falcon. Your humanoid appearance might have a patches of feathers, a bird's fan oof tails, a long nose, or such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skill Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Perception.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You have an avian aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny crow, owl, hawk, or falcon.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<!--Rodent-->
	<element name="Rodent Hengeyokai" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT_RODENT">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a simian aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny rat. Your humanoid appearance might have mice ears, rat's tail, or such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skill Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Stealth.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You have a rodent aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny rat.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Bnnuy-->
	<element name="Leporine Hengeyokai" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT_LEPORINE">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a leporine aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny hare. Your humanoid appearance might have hare ears, hare's tail, or such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skill Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Acrobatics.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You have a leporine aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny hare.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Vulpine-->
	<element name="Vulpine Hengeyokai" type="Sub Race" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Ancestries" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_RACES_RACIAL_TRAITS_HENGEYOKAI_ASPECT_VULPINE">
		<supports>Hengeyokai</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a leporine aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny fox. Your humanoid appearance might have fox ears, a fox's tails, or such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skill Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in Stealth.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<p>You have a vulpine aspect, and your animal form is a Tiny fox.</p>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
