<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Custom Magic Items</name>
		<description>Created for Sellswords Basin</description>
		<update version="0.0.26">
			<file name="items-magic.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aKromatopzia/Kolours-Aurora-Index/main/items/items-magic.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<!-- <! Kris of the Yusof Family > -->	
	<element name="Kris of the Yusof Family" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_YSUOF_KRIS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p>1/D, you can draw the weapon and the sword gains the effects of Spirit Guardians (Neutral, Necrotic) for 10 minutes or until it is sheathed. It cannot be unsheathed otherwise.</p>
			<p>Its wielder is immune to the effect. After 1 minute of being unsheathed, its wielder is also affected. After 10 minutes or if Spirit Guardians would be dispeled or cancelled, its sheath magically teleports back onto the blade unless it is on a different plane of existence or the sheath is magically suppressed. After it is re-sheathed, it can not be unsheathed until it regains its charge.</p>
			<p>If the sheath can't return to the blade by the duration's end, the blade becomes nonmagical until it is re-sheathed. The sheath will continually attempt to return to the blade.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">scimitar, sellswords, necrotic</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="scimitar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Scimitar</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Abyssal Huo-Chong" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_INFERNAL_HUO_CHONG">
		<description>
			<p>This hand cannon was constructed using materials from the plane of Abyss. In addition to its normal functions, the huo-chong has been modified to both act as a spellcasting focus and create its own ammunition when needed.</p>
			<p class="indent">Add your spellcasting ability modifier to Attack rolls and DCs of Attacks made with this weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a Bonus Action, the abyssal huo-chong can extend or retract a wooden rod with which to enable firing while held, or be deployed or retrieved.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon can be made to fire while it lacks a projectile and/or smokepowder by consuming the item’s charges or user’s spell slots. It has 1d3 charges, recharging each dusk. When used in this way, its damage dice is instead 2d8 for spread shots and 3d8 for single shots, increasing by 1d8 for each spell level over 1st or each additional charge used.</p> 
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">hand cannon</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type" addition="light hand cannon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Light Hand Cannon</set>
			<set name="charges">1d3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blue Flame Lancet" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_BLUE_FLAME_LANCET">
		<description>
			<p>A small razor with an a blade that is faintly wreathed in heatless blue flame. It has the potential to house 1 additional property.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Tattoo Attunement.</em></strong> To attune to this item, you hold the lancet to your skin where you want the tattoo to appear, pressing the lancet there throughout the attunement process. The tattoo itself is always at least fully covers one part of the attuned’s body; Optionally, you can trace and influence how the spellscar appears. When the attunement is complete, the lancet disappears. If your attunement to the scar ends, it vanishes, and the lancet reappears in your space.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Spellscarred.</em></strong> You gain the Spellscarred subtype.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Magical Strikes.</em></strong> While scarred, your weapon strikes are considered magical, and you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with melee strikes.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong>
					<em>Blue-Flame Strike.</em>
				</strong> When you make a melee attack (whether for the Attack action, Attack of Opportunity or similar), you can expend one Hit Dice to replace it with a spellfire-empowered strike. The target must make a DEX saving throw. They suffer the attack’s normal effects and take additional force damage equal to your Hit Dice on a failure, or only the force damage on a success. The DC of the save is equal to 8 + the bonuses you would have had to the attack. So long as the target takes damage from this attack, it counts as having hit.
			</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">tattoo, force</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Tattoo</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blue Flame Lancet [Blank]" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_BLUE_FLAME_LANCET_BLANK">
		<description>
			<p>A small razor with an a blade that is faintly wreathed in heatless blue flame. It has the potential to house 2 additional properties.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Tattoo Attunement.</em></strong> To attune to this item, you hold the lancet to your skin where you want the tattoo to appear, pressing the lancet there throughout the attunement process. The tattoo itself is always at least fully covers one part of the attuned’s body; Optionally, you can trace and influence how the spellscar appears. When the attunement is complete, the lancet disappears. If your attunement to the scar ends, it vanishes, and the lancet reappears in your space.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Spellscarred.</em></strong> You gain the Spellscarred subtype.</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">tattoo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Tattoo</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vigil's Claw" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_VIGILS_CLAW">
		<description>
			<p>The back of this wooden claw bears Bastet’s holy symbol. Due to its enchantments, divine and primal magics can be casted through it as a focus. Once used by members of the Lioness’ Vigil, one has been gifted to the guild.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong>
					<em>Lioness' Wrath.</em>
				</strong> As a Bonus Action, its wielder can Ready a spell. It can be maintained for up to a minute without requiring the caster’s concentration and is only expended on a hit. While a spell is readied in this manner, it can be delivered through an attack made with this weapon. The attack gains a bonus to hit equal to the spell’s level and cantrips are +0; The spell’s DC gains a bonus equal to the wielder’s STR or DEX, whichever was used for the attack. Once expended, the spell still needs to be concentrated upon.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">claw</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by someone who has the ability to cast from one of the Bard, Cleric, Druid, Paladin, Ranger spell lists">true</set>
			<set name="type" addition="claw">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Claw</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<!-- <! Gavel of Martial Symmetry > -->
	<element name="Gavel of Martial Symmetry" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_2WF_LIGHTHAMMER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p>While you are attuned to this weapon, whenever you attack with it as an off-hand weapon, it benefits from the Extra Attack feat, or similar feats.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">light hammer, sellswords</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="light hammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Light Hammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<!-- <! Wax & Wane > -->	
	<element name="Wax And Wane" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_LUNACY_AX">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p>Whenever wielded with one hand, or when wielded under the light of the moon, the wielder gains +1 to AC.</p>
			<p>Whenever wielded with two hands, or when wielded under the light of the moon, the weapon deals an additional 1d4 radiant damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">battleaxe, sellswords, radiant, armor class</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Sweetgum Shillelagh > -->	
	<element name="Sweetgum Shillelagh" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_SWEETGUM_SHILLELAGH">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon, and a character that has been hit by this weapon has its speed reduced by 5 feet until the end of its next turn.</p>
			<p>You can use your spellcasting ability instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of melee attacks using this weapon.</p>
			<p>You are proficient with this weapon if you are a druid.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">morningstar, sellswords, druid</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="morningstar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Morningstar</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Bolt of Light > -->	
	<element name="Bolt of Light" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_ARM_OF_LIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p>When you hurl it, its range changes to 120/120. The javelin forms a streak of light to its target, and on a hit, deals its weapon damage as radiant damage, and an additional 1d4 as radiant damage.</p>
			<p>Hit or miss, the weapon is then shunted into an extradimensional space. As part of an attack action, you can freely manifest the weapon into your hand.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">javelin, sellswords, radiant</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="javelin">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Javelin</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Wand of Missile" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_WAND_OF_MISSILE">
		<description>
			<p>As an Action, you can activate the switch on this wand causes it to fly away in the direction you're aiming it and deals 1 fire damage to you.</p>
			<p>Make a ranged [spell/weapon] attack with this wand. On a miss the wand goes wild, landing somewhere within 5 ft of your target. On a hit the target takes 2d6 bludgeoning damage, then bounces off to land within 5 ft of your target.</p>
			<p>After an attack roll is made with this weapon, roll a d20. On a 20 the wand explodes, dealing 8d6 fire damage to any creatures within 10ft of it's current location. Creatures that make a successful DC 13 Dexterity saving throw take half damage.</p>
			<p>This explosion destroys the wand.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wands</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wand</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Misting Censer" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_MISTING_CENSER">
		<description>
			<p>This bronze censer bears the reliefs of two men, one of which bears a falcon's head. The reliefs bear as indistinct mulanese style, seperate from the later Multhorand, Unther or Thay.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an Action, the censer can be made to magically produce a heavily obscuring fog for 1 minute, or until another Action is used to extinguish it. It spreads around corners up to 20ft. away from the censer, but only ever reaches up to a foot in height. Creatures that are flying but above the fog are still affected. This fog also has either of the following properties, as chosen or depending on the offering burnt:</p>
			<p class="indent">- [If holy water was offered,] The fog is difficult terrain for undead, fiends and abberations, and restores 1d4 hit points to any creature that isn't an undead, fiend or abberation if it would end its turn in the area.</p>
			<p class="indent">- [If unholy water was offered,] The fog is difficult terrain for celestials, fey and abberations, curses the area as the spell Desecrate, and each creature in the area takes an additional 1d4 necrotic damage from anything.</p>
			<p class="indent">This item can be used once before the next dawn or dusk, or whenever 1gp worth of silver dust, 1sp worth of incense, and a vial of either holy or unholy water is burnt, consuming the materials.</p> 
			<div element="ID_SELLSWORDS_SPELL_DESECRATE" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Helm of the Ram" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_RAM_HELM">
		<description>
			<p>This helmet magically changes its size and form to fit the wearer.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an Action, you can speak the command word to sprout ram horns. They last for 1 minute and can be used as a battering ram, granting a +5 bonus to Strength checks made to break through doors, barricades, and other barriers.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use the above property a number of times each day equal to your Proficiency Bonus.</p>
			<p class="indent">While the horns are active and you have moved at least 10ft in a straight line towards a creature, you can use a Bonus Action to strike it with your horns and Shove it. On a successful Shove, you also deal 2d4 bludgeoning damage.</p> 
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Dragon's Horn" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_DRAGONS_HORN">
		<description>
			<p>This polished, natural horn claims to be an instrument made of a hollowed out dragon's horn. Scrimshaw on the outside of the horn seems to tell the story of how the creature was slain. This horn comes in various damage types</p>
			<p class="indent"> As an action, you can play this instrument to create the 15 ft. cone or 30ft. line of a dragon breath weapon to the horn's colour. Each creature in the range makes a save where the DC is equal to 8 + Performance Modifier. Anyone who fails takes 3d10 damage, anyone who passes takes half that amount. The damage type, range and DC depend on the dragon-of-colour's breath weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">This feature cannot be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Shield of Shielding" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_SHIELD_OF_SHIELDING">
		<description>
			<p>The surface of this buckler has a layer of glass as tough as steel. You have a +1 to AC while using this shield.</p>
			<p class="indent">The shield's integrity can be restored by spending a long rest using Smithing Tools to tend to the shield's damage. This is reduced to a short rest if you are proficient with Smithing Tools. When the shield hits 0 AC it's properties are no longer usable until repaired.</p>
			<p class="indent">To Me! - As a reaction, you can choose to expend the shield's integrity to cast the Shield spell. The shield loses 1 AC.</p>
			<p class="indent">To You! - As a reaction, you can choose to expend the shield's integrity to intercept an attack on an ally within 5 feet of you when you see they are hit. Reduce the damage the target takes by 1d10 + Proficiency. The shield loses 1 AC.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Shielding</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:shield" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Mordenkainen's Missile Storm Staff" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_MISSILE_STORM_STAFF">
		<description>
			<p>This wizard's staff has an array of nine small gemstones surrounding one large gemstone embedded into the head of the staff. This staff can be used as a wizard's focus. </p>
			<p>Flickering Starlight - When a spell is cast within 100 feet of you, one of the small gemstones lights up. At round initiative 0, all of the staff's gemstones flicker out.</p>
			<p>Arrayed Burst - Once per day as an action, you can channel built up magic in the lit gemstones towards the large central one. Doing so casts Magic Missile of a level equal to the number of lit gemstones.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
		
	<!-- <! Bottomless Belt > -->			
		<element name="Bottomless Thunder-Bolt Belt" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_BOLT_BELT_THUNDER">
		<description>
			<p>This case of bolts straps nicely along the waist, and has a leather bandolier attached to it. It hums quietly.</p>
			<p>This bandolier can be fed into any crossbow, and when it is, that crossbow no longer has the Loading property, and deals an extra 2 Thunder damage on a hit.</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">belt, thunder</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">belt</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">waist</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Cloak of Daggers > -->		
		<element name="Cloak of Daggers" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_CLOAK_OF_DAGGERS">
		<description>
			<p>This black cloak has several sharp blades running around the bottom ring of it.</p>
			<p>While you are wearing it, you may use your bonus action to spin with it, causing it to cast the Sword Burst cantrip.</p>
			<p>The spell uses your level to determine its strength, and your dexterity score as its spellcasting ability modifier.</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cloak, force</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">cloak</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Aurixoths Rapier > -->	
	<element name="Aurixoth's Lost Rapier" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_AURIS_LOST_RAPIER">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p>You can sense that most of the magic seems to have faded from it, but the item retains a hint of what it used to be capable of. The handle is made with iridescent draconic scales, and the blade has a perfect silver sheen.</p>
			<p>Whenever you are holding this weapon, you may use it as a Bardic or Sorcerous spell focus, and are able to perform somatic components as if you had a free hand.</p>
			<p>You may also add your charisma modifier to the damage dealt by your cantrips that you cast while using it as a focus.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rapier, sellswords, sorcerer, bard</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="rapier">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="A bard or sorcerer">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Rapier</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Greataxe of Waylaying > -->	
	<element name="Greataxe of Waylaying" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_WAYLAYING_GREATAXE">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p>This enchantment on this greataxe is focused on the black leather grips that are attached to its dark wood frame, while it possesses a wicked golden blade.</p>
			<p>Hostile creatures that enter your threat range provoke an opportunity attack. If this attack hits, the creature's speed is set to 0 until the start of their next turn.</p>
			<p>This effect has a chance to recharge each round. At the end of each of your turns after this effect has been used, roll a d6, on a 6, you may use this effect again.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greataxe, sellswords</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greataxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greataxe</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
		<!-- <! Tattered Phoenix Cloak > -->		
	<element name="Tattered Phoenix Cloak" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_TATTERED_PHOENIX_CLOAK">
		<description>
			<p>This is the cloak you retrieved from the two strange bandits out on Snowflake mountains. It would look like any ordinary feather cloak, but the enchantment was placed on it when it was already torn and damaged.</p>
			<p>The feathers now softly glow like embers, providing bright light out to five feet, and dim light out to ten feet. The light can be dismissed as a free action.</p>
			<p>While you wear this cloak, a fiery warmth surges through you. You have resistance to fire and cold damage.</p>
			<p>As an action, you can draw upon the cloak to kindle a healing flame. A blaze begins to surround you, and you take 1d4 fire damage.</p>
			<p>After the damage is taken, you cast the Aura Of Vitality spell. Once this item is used this way, it cannot be used in the same way until the next dawn.</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cloak, fire, healing</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">cloak</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Ævor's Patch Kit > -->
	<element name="Ævor's Patch Kit" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_AEVORS_PATCH_KIT">
		<description>
			<p>This item resembles a painter's palette paired with a an oversized palette knife.</p>
			<p class="indent">The item has 6 charges and restores all of it's charges up to once per day by washing off built up residue of use from the item in magically created water This process takes a short rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you are attuned to this item, you can coat the palette knife on the palette with a pink crystal substance. This substance can be spread onto objects or air as you wish and hardens as soon as it's left behind into a rose tinted sturdy crystal.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><b>Sealant</b> - You can expend 1 charge as an action to apply a coating to seal any seam in an object (a door or chest for example.) The initial coating forces disadvantage on any checks to force a door open. Additional coatings will increase the HP of the door by 15 to ward off breaking it down.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Barrier</b> - For 3 charges you can create a flat barrier that covers a 5x5 area in front of you. Possible uses could be to create cover in an empty space, create a barrier over an archway, or any others you may think of. The barrier has an AC of 19 and 20 HP. Bludgeoning attacks have advantage against the barrier. Sealant can be used to patch up the barrier as well.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">barrier, sealant</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	
	<!-- <! Lobster Brooch > -->
	<element name="Lobster Brooch" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_LOBSTER_BROOCH">
		<description>
			<p>A lobster shaped brass brooch. Two small red gems are inlaid in the brooch to look like the creature's eyes.</p>
			
			<p class="indent">The item holds 3 charges and regains 1d4-1 charges each dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Carcinization</b> - As a bonus action, you can spend one charge to speak the brooch's command word. Doing so causes your hands to become large lobster claws for 1 minute. These give you advantage on any check in which you are "holding" something (ex. grapple, holding onto a ledge). The claws can also be used cut things. While your hands have been transformed, they cannot be used to hold items or equipment. Any items or weapons you are holding when you speak the command word fall to the ground. Your claws are natural weapons you are proficient in, with a d8 slashing damage dice.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Command Crab</b> - While your claws are out, you can opt to use your attack to make an attempt to restrain an enemy. Use the grapple rules for this attack.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">lobster, polymorphism, claws</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! The Weaver's Glove > -->
	<element name="The Weaver's Glove" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_WEAVERS_GLOVE">
		<description>
			<p>This delicate black glove is crafted of magically treated spidersilk. The holy symbol of Lolth, a spider as seen from above, is visible on the back of the hand.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><b>Chaos' Claim</b> - The wearer gains the ability to cast the mage hand cantrip. Your mage hand appears as a swarm of half-translucent spiders, crawling on spectral webs to reach their destination.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Nest</b> - Once per day, you can cast the Web spell. The spell has a DC of 13. Your spiders create the web in the spot you choose. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Swarm</b> - Once per day, you can cast the Cause Fear spell. The spell has a DC of 13. Your spiders swarm up the creature's body. On a successful save your target will see through them for the pseudo illusions they are.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">gloves, arachnid</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Amulet of Jarad > -->
	<element name="Amulet of Jarad" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_JARAD_AMULET">
		<description>
			<p>While you wear this amulet, your name is Jarad Bakerson. You are a human man in his late 30's. Your great grandfather was a baker. Your grandfather was a baker. Your father was a lich. You never met him though. You are a failed baker.</p>
			<p>Your current hobbies include walking around, sitting down unobtrusively, and having people walk away from you out of boredom when you speak. Your aunt died once, you didn't find out until a year later that they forgot to invite you to the funeral. You have an 8 in each of your stats. The only things you're proficient in are brooms.</p>
			<p>You've kept the same daily journal since you were 6. Most sections are written as follows: "(Year, Day, Month) Nothing interesting today".</p>
			<p>Your base movement speed is 25ft. You have a bad habit of dragging your feet, tripping because of it.</p>
			<p>The last words your mother said to you before she died was that she'd be happy to try your most recent pastry. Your brother is a famed and incredibly powerful sorcerer.</p>
			<p>Your spellcasting modifier is Charisma. The only magic you manifested was the On/Off cantrip. Due to a lack of any electronics in this century, you never realized it.</p>
			<p>When you were 4 you tripped in the cobblestone street, during this fall a shard of a Stone of Ill Luck managed to get lodged into your skin and healed over. You are attuned to it.</p>
			<p>Your current wardrobe consists of 2 stained shirts and a pair of pants with a hole in the knee.</p>
			<p>You own a Viol, it's the most expensive item you own. It belonged to your grandmother. She left it to her daughter, your mother, and she left it to you because she wanted you out of the house and was hoping you could do something with it. You've been trying to learn it for 12 years, you do not have proficiency in the Viol.</p>
			<p>You have disadvantage on persuasion checks to convince people to meet you again at a later date. You have an allergy to grains. This effect ends when you take off the amulet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">amulet, jarad, what</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Oprase-Lens Glasses > -->
	<element name="Oprase-Lens Glasses" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_OPRASE_LENS_GLASSES">
		<description>
			<p>Forged by a cleric of Tymora, these glasses allow the wearer to make their own luck, at a cost befitting her lady of course. What reward is not sweeter without risk after all? And what risk is better than as an offering to the Lady?</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><b>Press Your Luck</b> - You can choose to turn any attack roll that you've already hit, before damage is dealt, into a Natural 20. If you do, reduce your proficiency bonus by 1. This effect cannot be used if your proficiency bonus is already 0.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Reap What You Sow</b> - When you roll a Natural 20 on a d20, you can choose to instead treat that roll as a Natural 0. If you do, your proficiency bonus increases by 1, up to your maximum.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Nothing Ventured, Nothing Gained</b> - As punishment for a perceived folding in one of her games, the glasses cause a dependence to the user after they've been unattuned. For 1d4 weeks after using the glasses, your Critical Hits will be treated as Critical Failures. Once the curse has passed naturally, your proficiency bonus returns to it's maximum, excepting outstanding other effects.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">glasses, luck</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Shower Rod > -->
	<element name="Shower Rod" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_SHOWER_ROD">
		<description>
			<p>This item appears to be a plain aluminum rod with a knob at each end and a two hooks, one at each end. A sign at the top appears reading, "Leave your (extradimensional) bags at the door.", with an arrow pointing to either hook.</p>
			<p class="indent">Light and about 3 feet long. When you speak it's command word, the rod will attempt to drop an opaque white vinyl curtain with a blue floral pattern beneath it. If there isn't enough room to do so, it will find the closest viable space.</p>
			<p class="indent">Behind the curtain lies a luxurious shower in an extra dimensional space. 5ft x 5ft heated stone floors, Four showerheads, and it's own stock of soaps, shampoos, and other needs. To the side is a section of wall that can be opened, any clothes placed inside of it will be freshly laundered after 10 minutes inside.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><b>Shower Thoughts</b> - While any creature is making use of the item's facilities, that creature has advantage on any Intelligence or Wisdom checks.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! White Dragon's Scales Tattoo > -->
	<element name="White Dragon's Scales Tattoo" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_WHITE_DRAGON_TATTOO">
		<description>
			<p class="indent">Tattoo Attunement - To attune to this item, you hold the needle to your skin where you want the tattoo to appear, pressing the needle there throughout the attunement process. When the attunement is complete, the needle turns into the ink that becomes the tattoo, which appears on the skin.</p>
		
			<p class="indent"><b>Scaled Protection</b> - While you're attuned to this item, white scales manifest on your body in addition to the tattoo. You may have your AC be equal to 13+ Dex Mod. Additionally, you gain a resistance to cold damage and a vulnerability to fire damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">tattoo, armor, cold</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Tattoo</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Fantastical Fanny Pack > -->
	<element name="Fantastical Fanny Pack" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_FANNY_PACK">
		<description>
			<p>This Fanny Pack contains an extradimensional space.</p>
			<p class="indent">It can hold up to 8 cubic feet or 80 pounds of material. The pack always weighs 2 pounds, regardless of its contents.</p>
			<p class="indent">Placing an object in the Fanny Pack follows the normal rules for interacting with objects. Retrieving an item from the pack requires you to use an action. When you reach into the pack for a specific item, the item is always magically on top. </p>
			<p class="indent">If overloaded, pierced, or torn, the pack ruptures and is destroyed. If the pack is destroyed, its contents are lost forever, although an artifact always turns up again somewhere. If the pack is turned inside out, its contents spill forth, unharmed, and the pack must be put right before it can be used again. If a breathing creature is placed within the pack, the creature can survive up to 10 minutes, after which time it begins to suffocate.</p>
			<p class="indent">Placing the pack inside an extradimensional space created by a bag of holding, portable hole, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10 feet of the gate is sucked through it and deposited in a random location on the Astral Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can't be reopened.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bag, holding, hideous</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="slot">waist</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Combo Bracers > -->
	<element name="Combo Bracers" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_COMBO_BRACERS">
		<description>
			<p>A matching set of four bracers for wrists and ankles.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit a melee weapon attack on your turn, if this is the first melee weapon attack you've hit against this enemy this turn, gain an extra 10ft of movement this turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">gloves, movement, combo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Binding Stone > -->
	<element name="Binding Stone" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_BINDING_STONE">
		<description>
			<p>Despite appearing to be a normal cobblestone, it reflects the image of creatures in it's surface.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">stone, rock, mineral, something</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Adamantine Hot Plate > -->
	<element name="Adamantine Hot Plate" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_ADAMANTINE_HOT_PLATE">
		<description>
			<p>This hot plate, enchanted with a toggleable Heat Metal, can be used for all your cooking needs! It's large size makes it perfect for just about any pan or pot you can find for it.</p>
			<p>Huh? The straps on the underside of it? We used an old shield to make it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cooking, tools</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Cordio's Portable Spicerack > -->
	<element name="Cordio's Portable Spicerack" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_PORTABLE_SPICERACK">
		<description>
			<p>This small wooden box with a lid can visibly hold up to three spice bottles inside of it. When you close the lid, you can speak the name of up to 3 known commonly used spices for cooking. </p>
			
			<p class="indent"><b>Well Stocked</b> - When the lid is next opened, the requested spices will be available.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Well Seasoned</b> - When you use this item while making an ability check involving cooking tools, treat the roll as if you have proficiency. If you already have proficiency, treat the roll as if you have expertise.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Well Fed</b> - As part of a short rest, you can cook special food with this item provided you have ingredients and cook's utensils on hand. You can prepare enough of this food for a number of creatures equal to 4 + your proficiency bonus. At the end of the short rest, any creature who eats the food and spends one or more Hit Dice to regain hit points regains an extra 1d8 hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cooking</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Poisoner's Bracers > -->
	<element name="Poisoner's Bracers" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_POISONERS_BRACERS">
		<description>
			<p>These enchanted bracers seem to disappear once attuned, blending into the color and texture of your wrists beneath them. Notable small hidden pouches and slots allow you to store your poisons for easy use.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><b>Efficacy</b> - When you make a damage roll that deals poison damage, it ignores resistance to poison damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Efficiency</b> - You can apply poison to a weapon or piece of ammunition as a bonus action instead of an action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">gloves, poison</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Lightning Rod > -->
	<element name="Lightning Rod" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_LIGHTNING_ROD">
		<description>
			<p>This Copper quarterstaff hums gently with it's own magical current. This staff can act as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><b>Conductor</b> - While you're holding this weapon, you have disadvantage on any saving throws to prevent or reduce lightning damage and attacks that deal lightning damage have advantage against you. The weapon will block lightning damage equal to the number of empty charges it has up to a maximum of 6, converting it into charges. The weapon cannot be used to charge itself. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Shock</b> - Pay 2 charges on a weapon attack hit: add 2d6 lightning to your damage dice.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Bolt</b> - Recharge 5-6 - Pay 6 charges as an action: Cast a 3rd level lightning bolt. The staff's overheat deals 1d6 fire damage to you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">staff, lightning, magic</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Portable Puddle > -->
	<element name="Portable Puddle" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_PORTABLE_PUDDLE">
		<description>
			<p>This Portable Hole is always filled with water when you lay it out.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you lay this item out, roll 1d4. That many frogs live in the puddle at this time.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">water, puddle, frogs</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--Vayemniri Enforcer's Bigonne-->
	<element name="Vayemniri Enforcer's Bigonne" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_VAYEMNIRI_ENFORCER">
		<description>
			<p>The pistol has ornamental iron plates on each side, both with an engraving depicting a serpent coiled and prepared to strike, resting upon a fountain pen as if it were on a branch. Within the firearm's handle is a hatch that holds up to two small bullets. Upon the handle is another metal plate, upon which "Korygh" is engraved phonetically in Abeiran Draconic.</p>
			<p class="indent">This firearm can be used as an arcane focus, and you have a +2 to the DC of spells cast using this weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">This item has 2 charges which manifest as bullets in its handle's cavity. It regenerates these bullets daily at dusk.</p>
			<p class="indent">When fired, the magical bullets cause a beam of arcane energy to streak towards a creature you can see within 60ft. The target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed for 1 minute. At the end of each of the target's turns, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p> 
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Pocket Bigonne</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by someone with the Spellcasting or Pact Magic features">true</set>
			<set name="type" addition="pocket bigonne">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Pocket Bigonne</set>
			<set name="charges">2</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="2" bonus="vayemniri enforcer's gonne"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<!--Lunar Blessing-->
	<element name="Lunar Blessing" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_LUNAR_BLESSING">
		<description>
			<p>This ring has been crafted with twines of a hardened mystic branch. It's embellished with a glittery stone insignia representing the full moon. It protects the wearer with an intensity proportional to the moonlight.</p>
			<p>If the user is exposed to the moon, all incoming damage is reduced depending on its current phase. In the event of a lunar eclipse, damage will be reduced with respect to the moon's exposure.</p>
			<ul>New Moon: No reduction</ul>
			<ul>Crescent Moon: 1 hitpoints of damage</ul>
			<ul>Half Moon: 2 hitpoints of damage</ul>
			<ul>Gibbous Moon: 3 hitpoints of damage</ul>
			<ul>Full Moon: 4 hitpoints of damage</ul>
			
			<p>
				In the event of a solar eclipse, all rolls will gain an additional +1 boost regardless of totality.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">moon, blessing, lunar, reduction</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
</elements>
