<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Custom Magic Items</name>
		<description>Created for Sellswords Basin</description>
		<update version="0.0.16">
			<file name="items-magic.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aKromatopzia/Kolours-Aurora-Index/main/items/items-magic.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Abyssal Huo-Chong" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_INFERNAL_HUO_CHONG">
		<description>
			<p>This hand cannon was constructed using materials from the plane of Abyss. In addition to its normal functions, the huo-chong has been modified to both act as a spellcasting focus and create its own ammunition when needed.</p>
			<p class="indent">Add your spellcasting ability modifier to Attack rolls and DCs of Attacks made with this weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a Bonus Action, the abyssal huo-chong can extend or retract a wooden rod with which to enable firing while held, or be deployed or retrieved.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon can be made to fire while it lacks a projectile and/or smokepowder by consuming the item’s charges or user’s spell slots. It has 1d3 charges, recharging each dusk. When used in this way, its damage dice is instead 2d8 for spread shots and 3d8 for single shots, increasing by 1d8 for each spell level over 1st or each additional charge used.</p> 
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">hand cannon</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type" addition="light hand cannon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Light Hand Cannon</set>
			<set name="charges">1d3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blue Flame Lancet" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_BLUE_FLAME_LANCET">
		<description>
			<p>A small razor with an a blade that is faintly wreathed in heatless blue flame. It has the potential to house 1 additional property.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Tattoo Attunement.</em></strong> To attune to this item, you hold the lancet to your skin where you want the tattoo to appear, pressing the lancet there throughout the attunement process. The tattoo itself is always at least fully covers one part of the attuned’s body; Optionally, you can trace and influence how the spellscar appears. When the attunement is complete, the lancet disappears. If your attunement to the scar ends, it vanishes, and the lancet reappears in your space.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Spellscarred.</em></strong> You gain the Spellscarred subtype.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Magical Strikes.</em></strong> While scarred, your weapon strikes are considered magical, and you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with melee strikes.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong>
					<em>Blue-Flame Strike.</em>
				</strong> When you make a melee attack (whether for the Attack action, Attack of Opportunity or similar), you can expend one Hit Dice to replace it with a spellfire-empowered strike. The target must make a DEX saving throw. They suffer the attack’s normal effects and take additional force damage equal to your Hit Dice on a failure, or only the force damage on a success. The DC of the save is equal to 8 + the bonuses you would have had to the attack. So long as the target takes damage from this attack, it counts as having hit.
			</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">tattoo, force</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Tattoo</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blue Flame Lancet [Blank]" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_BLUE_FLAME_LANCET_BLANK">
		<description>
			<p>A small razor with an a blade that is faintly wreathed in heatless blue flame. It has the potential to house 2 additional properties.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Tattoo Attunement.</em></strong> To attune to this item, you hold the lancet to your skin where you want the tattoo to appear, pressing the lancet there throughout the attunement process. The tattoo itself is always at least fully covers one part of the attuned’s body; Optionally, you can trace and influence how the spellscar appears. When the attunement is complete, the lancet disappears. If your attunement to the scar ends, it vanishes, and the lancet reappears in your space.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong><em>Spellscarred.</em></strong> You gain the Spellscarred subtype.</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">tattoo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Tattoo</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vigil's Claw" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_VIGILS_CLAW">
		<description>
			<p>The back of this wooden claw bears Bastet’s holy symbol. Due to its enchantments, divine and primal magics can be casted through it as a focus. Once used by members of the Lioness’ Vigil, one has been gifted to the guild.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<strong>
					<em>Lioness' Wrath.</em>
				</strong> As a Bonus Action, its wielder can Ready a spell. It can be maintained for up to a minute without requiring the caster’s concentration and is only expended on a hit. While a spell is readied in this manner, it can be delivered through an attack made with this weapon. The attack gains a bonus to hit equal to the spell’s level and cantrips are +0; The spell’s DC gains a bonus equal to the wielder’s STR or DEX, whichever was used for the attack. Once expended, the spell still needs to be concentrated upon.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">claw</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by someone who has the ability to cast from one of the Bard, Cleric, Druid, Paladin, Ranger spell lists">true</set>
			<set name="type" addition="claw">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Claw</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<!-- <! Gavel of Martial Symmetry > -->
	<element name="Gavel of Martial Symmetry" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_2WF_LIGHTHAMMER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p>While you are attuned to this weapon, whenever you attack with it as an off-hand weapon, it benefits from the Extra Attack feat, or similar feats.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">light hammer, sellswords</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="light hammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Light Hammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<!-- <! Wax & Wane > -->	
	<element name="Wax And Wane" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_LUNACY_AX">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p>Whenever wielded with one hand, or when wielded under the light of the moon, the wielder gains +1 to AC.</p>
			<p>Whenever wielded with two hands, or when wielded under the light of the moon, the weapon deals an additional 1d4 radiant damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">battleaxe, sellswords, radiant, armor class</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Sweetgum Shillelagh > -->	
	<element name="Sweetgum Shillelagh" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_SWEETGUM_SHILLELAGH">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon, and a character that has been hit by this weapon has its speed reduced by 5 feet until the end of its next turn.</p>
			<p>You can use your spellcasting ability instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of melee attacks using this weapon.</p>
			<p>You are proficient with this weapon if you are a druid.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">morningstar, sellswords, druid</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="morningstar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Morningstar</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- <! Bolt of Light > -->	
	<element name="Bolt of Light" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_ARM_OF_LIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p>When you hurl it, its range changes to 120/120. The javelin forms a streak of light to its target, and on a hit, deals its weapon damage as radiant damage, and an additional 1d4 as radiant damage.</p>
			<p>Hit or miss, the weapon is then shunted into an extradimensional space. As part of an attack action, you can freely manifest the weapon into your hand.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">javelin, sellswords, radiant</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="javelin">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Javelin</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Wand of Missile" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_WAND_OF_MISSILE">
		<description>
			<p>As an Action, you can activate the switch on this wand causes it to fly away in the direction you're aiming it and deals 1 fire damage to you.</p>
			<p>Make a ranged [spell/weapon] attack with this wand. On a miss the wand goes wild, landing somewhere within 5 ft of your target. On a hit the target takes 2d6 bludgeoning damage, then bounces off to land within 5 ft of your target.</p>
			<p>After an attack roll is made with this weapon, roll a d20. On a 20 the wand explodes, dealing 8d6 fire damage to any creatures within 10ft of it's current location. Creatures that make a successful DC 13 Dexterity saving throw take half damage.</p>
			<p>This explosion destroys the wand.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wands</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wand</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Misting Censer" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_MISTING_CENSER">
		<description>
			<p>This bronze censer bears the reliefs of two men, one of which bears a falcon's head. The reliefs bear as indistinct mulanese style, seperate from the later Multhorand, Unther or Thay.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an Action, the censer can be made to magically produce a heavily obscuring fog for 1 minute, or until another Action is used to extinguish it. It spreads around corners up to 20ft. away from the censer, but only ever reaches up to a foot in height. Creatures that are flying but above the fog are still affected. This fog also has either of the following properties, as chosen or depending on the offering burnt:</p>
			<p class="indent">- [If holy water was offered,] The fog is difficult terrain for undead, fiends and abberations, and restores 1d4 hit points to any creature that isn't an undead, fiend or abberation if it would end its turn in the area.</p>
			<p class="indent">- [If unholy water was offered,] The fog is difficult terrain for celestials, fey and abberations, curses the area as the spell Desecrate, and each creature in the area takes an additional 1d4 necrotic damage from anything.</p>
			<p class="indent">This item can be used once before the next dawn or dusk, or whenever 1gp worth of silver dust, 1sp worth of incense, and a vial of either holy or unholy water is burnt, consuming the materials.</p> 
			<div element="ID_SELLSWORDS_SPELL_DESECRATE" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Helm of the Ram" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_RAM_HELM">
		<description>
			<p>This helmet magically changes its size and form to fit the wearer.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an Action, you can speak the command word to sprout ram horns. They last for 1 minute and can be used as a battering ram, granting a +5 bonus to Strength checks made to break through doors, barricades, and other barriers.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use the above property a number of times each day equal to your Proficiency Bonus.</p>
			<p class="indent">While the horns are active and you have moved at least 10ft in a straight line towards a creature, you can use a Bonus Action to strike it with your horns and Shove it. On a successful Shove, you also deal 2d4 bludgeoning damage.</p> 
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Dragon's Horn" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_DRAGONS_HORN">
		<description>
			<p>This polished, natural horn claims to be an instrument made of a hollowed out dragon's horn. Scrimshaw on the outside of the horn seems to tell the story of how the creature was slain. This horn comes in various damage types</p>
			<p class="indent"> As an action, you can play this instrument to create the 15 ft. cone or 30ft. line of a dragon breath weapon to the horn's colour. Each creature in the range makes a save where the DC is equal to 8 + Performance Modifier. Anyone who fails takes 3d10 damage, anyone who passes takes half that amount. The damage type, range and DC depend on the dragon-of-colour's breath weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">This feature cannot be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Shield of Shielding" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_SHIELD_OF_SHIELDING">
		<description>
			<p>The surface of this buckler has a layer of glass as tough as steel. You have a +1 to AC while using this shield.</p>
			<p class="indent">The shield's integrity can be restored by spending a long rest using Smithing Tools to tend to the shield's damage. This is reduced to a short rest if you are proficient with Smithing Tools. When the shield hits 0 AC it's properties are no longer usable until repaired.</p>
			<p class="indent">To Me! - As a reaction, you can choose to expend the shield's integrity to cast the Shield spell. The shield loses 1 AC.</p>
			<p class="indent">To You! - As a reaction, you can choose to expend the shield's integrity to intercept an attack on an ally within 5 feet of you when you see they are hit. Reduce the damage the target takes by 1d10 + Proficiency. The shield loses 1 AC.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Shielding</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:shield" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Mordenkainen's Missile Storm Staff" type="Magic Item" source="Sellsword Stuff: Custom Magic Items" id="ID_SELLSWORDS_MAGIC_ITEMS_MISSILE_STORM_STAFF">
		<description>
			<p>This wizard's staff has an array of nine small gemstones surrounding one large gemstone embedded into the head of the staff. This staff can be used as a wizard's focus. </p>
			<p>Flickering Starlight - When a spell is cast within 100 feet of you, one of the small gemstones lights up. At round initiative 0, all of the staff's gemstones flicker out.</p>
			<p>Arrayed Burst - Once per day as an action, you can channel built up magic in the lit gemstones towards the large central one. Doing so casts Magic Missile of a level equal to the number of lit gemstones.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
