<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Sellswords Features</name>
		<description>Created for Sellswords Basin</description>
		<update version="0.1.4">
			<file name="sellsword-features.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aKromatopzia/Kolours-Aurora-Index/main/Sellswords-Features/sellsword-features.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Psionic Awakening" type="Feat" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Features" id="ID_SELLSWORD_FEAT_PSIONIC_AWAKENING">
		<prerequisite>???</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p><i>???</i></p>
			<p>You have learnt to manifest your will with a thought.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You learn one psionic talent and one psionic discipline from the mystic's class, and you are capable of focusing on that discipline.</li>
				<li>You gain 2 psi points to spend on psionic disciplines, and have a psi limit of 2. You regain all spent psi points when you finish a long rest.</li>
				<li>Your psionic ability modifier is Intelligence.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain 2 psi points to spend on psionic disciplines, are capable of focusing on that discipline, and have a psi limit of 2. You regain all spent psi points when you finish a long rest. Your psionic ability modifier is Intelligence.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talents (Psionic Awakening)" supports="Psionic Talents" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Psionic Discipline (Psionic Awakening)" supports="Psionic Disciplines"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Vital Sacrifice" type="Feat" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Features" id="ID_SELLSWORD_FEAT_VITAL_SACRIFICE">
		<description>
			<p>You've learned secrets of blood magic that grant you heightened power at the price of your own life force.</p>
			<p>You increase your Constitution or Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
			<p>As part of an action, you can choose to take 1d6 necrotic damage to gain one of the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>When you miss with an attack roll, you may roll 1d6 and add it to the total.</li>
				<li>When you deal damage with an attack or spell, you deal an additional necrotic damage equal to 1d6 + your proficiency bonus.</li>
				<li>When you cause a creature to make a Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution saving throw, roll a d4 and reduce their save by the amount rolled.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Damage you take from this feature can’t be reduced in any way, and it ignores temporary hitpoints. The damage taken does not disrupt your Concentration.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You may take 1d6 unmitigated necrotic damage to:
			Add 1d6 to a missed attack roll.
			Add an additional 1d6 + {{proficiency}} to damage dealt with an attack or spell.
			Reduce the result of a Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution save that you caused by 1d4.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Vital Sacrifice)" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Grappler (5.5e)" type="Feat" source="Sellsword's Stuff: Features" id="ID_SELLSWORD_FEAT_GRAPPLER">
		<prerequisite>Strength or Dexterity 13 or higher</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:4],[str:13]||[dex:13]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You gain the following benefits.</p>
			<p><b>Ability Score Increase.</b> Increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
			<p><b>Punch and Grab.</b> When you hit a creature with an <i>Unarmed Strike</i> as part of the <i>Attack</i> action on your turn, you can use both the Damage and the Grapple option. You can use this benefit only once per turn.</p>
			<p><b>Attack Advantage.</b> You have <i>Advantage</i> on attack rolls against a creature <i>Grappled</i> by you.</p>
			<p><b>Fast Wrestler</b> You don't have to spend extra movement to move a creature <i>Grappled</i> by you if this creature is your size or smaller.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				When you hit a creature with an Unarmed Strike as part of the Attack action on your turn, you can use both the Damage and the Grapple option once per turn. 
				You have Advantage on attack rolls against a creature Grappled by you. 
				You don't have to spend extra movement to move a creature Grappled by you if this creature is your size or smaller.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Grappler 5.5e)" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
</elements>
