<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>	
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Mystic "Unbound"</name>
		<update version="0.0.3">
			<file name="mystic-unbound.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aKromatopzia/Kolours-Aurora-Index/main/Class-Edits/mystic-unbound.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Psionic Restoration" type="Spell" source="Sellsword Reworks" id="ID_SELLSWORD_REWORKS_SPELL_MYSTIC_PSIONIC_RESTORATION">
		<supports>Psionic Disciplines</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WOTC_UA20170313_CLASS_MYSTIC||ID_WOTC_UA20170313_MULTICLASS_MYSTIC</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You wield psionic energy to cure wounds and restore health to yourself and others.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Psychic Focus.</b> While focused on this discipline, you can use a bonus action to touch a creature that has 0 hit points and stabilize it.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Mend Wounds (1–7 psi).</b> As an action, you can spend psi points to restore hit points to one creature you touch. The creature regains 1d8 hit points per psi point spent.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Restore Health (3 psi).</b> As an action, you touch one creature and remove one of the following conditions from it: blinded, deafened, paralyzed, or poisoned. Alternatively, you remove one disease from the creature.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Vim Pulse (5 psi).</b> As an action, you expel a psychic force to mend that which is broken. All creatures in a 20ft. of yourself heal for 4d8 hit points. This does not affect Constructs.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Restore Vigor (7 psi) .</b> As an action, you can touch one creature and choose one of the following: remove any reductions to one of its ability scores, remove one effect that reduces its hit point maximum, or reduce its exhaustion level by one.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Immortal Discipline</set>
			<set name="time">Variable</set>
			<set name="duration">Variable</set>
			<set name="range">Variable</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"></set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Blind Spot" type="Class Feature" source="Sellsword Reworks" id="ID_SELLSWORD_REWORKS_MYSTIC_TALENTS_BLIND_SPOT">
		<supports>Psionic Talents</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you erase your image from the mind of one creature you can see within 120 feet of you; the target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw, or you are invisible to it until the end of your next turn. A creature that can not be charmed is immune to this effect. Additionally, the creature has advantage on the saving throw if they are in active pursuit of or thinking about you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As an action, you erase your image from the mind of one creature you can see within 120 feet of you; the target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw, or you are invisible to it until the end of your next turn. A creature that can not be charmed is immune to this effect. Additionally, the creature has advantage on the saving throw if they are in active pursuit of or thinking about you.</description>
		</sheet>
</elements>
